Today, I'm showing you how to use AI
tools to make a professional commercial
that looks like this.
>> [music]
>> Welcome back to the channel, and if
you're new here, my name is Thomas, and
I make videos about AI product
photography. In my previous video, I
tested Nano Banana 2 for food
photography for a burger chain I made
up, and doing that sparked an idea in my
head. I wanted to see if I could create
an epic B-roll style food commercial
only using AI tools. So, I started
searching for epic B-roll commercials on
YouTube and landed on this epic pizza
B-roll by Daniel Schiffer. I wanted to
see if I could create something of
similar quality without even touching a
camera or leaving my house, but only
using AI tools. First of all, we needed
a pizza and a pizza brand to create the
commercial around, so that's how I
created La Pizza The Subscribe. From
there, the next step was to start
creating the individual frames of the
different clips from the commercial. To
generate the images and videos in this
commercial, I used Higgsfield AI, and
this video is not sponsored by them, but
if you want to do this for yourself, I
think I have a discount code in the
description below. I really liked the
intro in Daniel Schiffer's commercial,
so I started by taking some inspiration
from that and taking screenshots of the
frames and asking ChatGPT to describe a
similar scene, but with my brand colors.
Then, using the prompts that we got from
ChatGPT, I used Nano Banana Pro to
create frames for the three first shots
of the commercial. For the next three
shots, I wanted a sequence where the
chef's hand is pouring and spreading the
tomato sauce on the pizza dough. And
already before creating the motion for
the frames, I had in mind what type of
movement I wanted to see in the sequence
in order for the clips to flow together
in a nice way in the final edit. During
the short sequence of three clips, I
wanted a hand to move from left to right
and then finally cut to an overhead shot
with the finalizing touches of the
movement. The next three shots was the
cheese dripping down, the chef cutting
the mushroom, and then the pepperoni
falling towards the pizza. The cheese
and pepperoni one weren't that
complicated to create, but for the
mushroom one, I knew that I could create
a start and end frame for the action
that would then flow perfectly when you
animate it. I was able to create the
last frame of the shot where the
mushroom is being cut quite easily, but
for some reason, I was really struggling
by creating the first frame where the
chef is holding the knife like this. So,
here's a pro tip for you, how to get a
really specific angle that might be hard
to explain to an AI. So, what I did was
I took an iPhone photo of me holding up
the knife like this, and then uploaded
that to Nano Banana Pro and asked it to
turn it into a sketch. Now, by doing
this, I had a sketch of the image I
wanted, and I could use the last frame
as a style reference for the sketch. So,
I asked Nano Banana Pro to create a
photorealistic image of the sketch in
the exact same environment as the last
frame, and this is the result we got.
So, this is something you can do in
other instances as well. If you're
struggling to get the AI to understand
you, try uploading a sketch of the exact
composition you want, and then a style
reference where it can pull the
photographic style onto that sketch.
Next up, I knew I wanted a few close-up
frames of the purple onion being placed
on the pizza and then transitioning into
the chef picking it up with the pizza
shovel. Pizza shovel, pizza peel, you
know, the thing that you pick up the
pizza with. For the frame of the hand
picking up the purple onion from the
jar, I actually used a previous
generation version of the hand holding
the cheese that I ended up not using.
So, in this way, you can also kind of
form your style as you go and use
generations that maybe wasn't fit for
one purpose, and you can use it to
generate something else. Then, for the
last shots of the commercial, we needed
frames for the shots where the chef is
putting the pizza inside the oven, the
pizza being baked in the oven, and then
the final product being presented to the
camera. And for these final frames, I
actually first didn't have the idea of
having the time-lapse transition between
the unbaked and the baked pizza, but
this is something also where AI
workflows are really powerful because
when you jump into the editing and find
out that you need something else or need
a completely different shot, then you
can just create it instead of being
stuck in a position where you don't have
the material from the day you were
shooting the actual commercial. When we
had generated all the frames for the
different shots of the commercial, it
was time to start animating them using
Kling 3.0. The process looks pretty much
the same as when creating the frames for
the commercial. First, I go to ChatGPT
and tell it that I'm using Kling 3.0 and
want to create this type of shot using
this image. This way, I will get quite a
good base prompt to use along with the
image in Kling 3.0. Now, for this
commercial specifically, and I recommend
you do this for most product
commercials, I asked specifically for
super slow motion shots. The reason we
do this is because when we jump into the
editing software, we have more
flexibility when we want to re-time the
clip if it's already in slow motion. If
we generate clips in normal speed using
Kling 3.0, we can't in the editing
software slow it down to slow motion
without getting some artifacts. So,
asking for a slow motion clip is usually
better because it gives you more
flexibility when re-timing the clips
later. And when generating video clips
using Kling 3.0 or basically any video
generator for that matter, it's a bit of
a trial and error. You have to tweak the
prompt sometimes because usually it's
not perfect on the first generation and
even doing two generations with the
exact same prompt might give you a
slightly different result. And this can
definitely be frustrating if you're
trying to do just a simple action. For
example, when I wanted the hand to take
the sauce out of the bucket, it kept on
generating the hand pouring the sauce
into the bucket, which wasn't what I was
looking for. So, sometimes you have to
be a bit creative and maybe using like a
start and end frame to lock in that
motion, like I did in the knife example,
which basically was, I think, two
generations and I got it perfect. But if
I can give you any tips from my
experience and struggle of using these
tools, I can tell you that it's never
good to trying to force the AI to follow
your instructions. If you notice that it
keeps on doing the same mistake, then
maybe take another approach or use a
start and end frame to really lock that
specific motion in. Otherwise, you can
get stuck in a loop where you're just
trying to get it to understand what you
want and sometimes it just doesn't. And
another tip I would give you is try to
look at the individual clips more like a
photographer. So, they don't have to be
perfect from start to finish every
single second, but maybe there's a three
or five second slice of the clip that
can be used. And in that way, if you
bring it to the editing software, you
can still have some good material from
the slightly wonky clip. For example,
when making this commercial, there were
several of the shots that was kind of
wonky at times, but then they had this
2-second slice that was perfect and
exactly what I was looking for. So, I
used that part and then just discarded
the rest in post-production. Now that we
had generated all the clips using Kling
3.0, it was time to jump into the
editing software and cut them all
together with music and sound effects.
This is what the timeline looks like in
my editing software for the commercial.
I have used very basic editing
techniques that you can use in basically
any editing software that you like. So,
for example, CapCut, Final Cut Pro,
Premiere Pro, or DaVinci Resolve all can
do these things that I'm about to show
you. The first thing I usually do is
select a music track that I want to use
because that way you can edit to the
music and cut to the beat, which makes
it feel so much more professional if
your visuals actually flow with the
music. I get all my music and sound
effects from Artlist, and if you want to
use the exact same that I did, then
there's a link in the description below,
and I think you can get 2 months free
through that link as well. For the
visual editing, it basically comes down
to three techniques that I've used. It's
retiming effects or speed ramps, some
simple zoom effects, and then some
transitions. We're going to use the
first clips of the commercial as an
example of how to use these effects and
really elevate your AI visuals. In the
very first clip of the commercial, as
the camera is moving towards the ball of
pizza dough at the end of the tunnel,
you can see that I have both added a
slight zoom in and adjusted the speed of
the clip according to the action when
the hand is entering the frame. Then,
when the hand is just about to grab the
ball of pizza dough, I have slowed it
down again and then sped it up with a
transition to the next shot. And I knew
I wanted to transition from this shot
upwards, so I intentionally chose a
transition that flows very good between
the shots that makes it feel natural and
guides the viewers' attention upwards.
And when we enter the next shot, I have
also sped up the beginning of that shot
to create a smooth as possible of a
transition in order for it to feel
seamless. And by using this method
throughout your videos, you can really
create some smooth motion from shot to
shot by having one shot ending in a
direction and another shot beginning in
the same direction. So, that way it
feels like the shots flow together in a
totally different way compared to just
having them after one another. And here
you can also get creative. For example,
this final shot of the pizza being
presented was actually reversed because
the generation that I created wasn't
quite good, but I saw that if I just
take the beginning of that shot and
reverse it, it will look quite okay with
the chef bringing it back as a showcase.
When I have done the visual edits to the
music, then I usually add sound effects
for transitions and impacts and
different elements of the commercial
that really brings it to life. And just
to show you the difference that sound
effects make, here is the commercial
without music and only sound effects.
Now, we have generated the whole
commercial only using AI tools, but was
it actually worth it compared to a
traditional product photography
workflow? If we look at the quality side
of things, the resolution is 1080p, so
they are of course lower quality than if
we we film them on a professional
camera. There can also be some wonkiness
sometimes in a clip. For example, in
this one where the pepperonis are
warping in a weird way. So, you have to
be really careful when generating if
you're going to do professional work
that there is no warping in your
footage. Then, looking at the workflow
itself, it's much more smooth using the
AI tools than actually doing the
production yourself. I would first of
all have had to schedule a day for the
photo shoot, book a talent for that
photo shoot, then either own or rent
expensive gear to make it happen. And
then in the editing, using traditional
methods, I can't retake a shot or
regenerate anything, but I'm stuck with
what I got on the day. If we would use a
combination of traditional and AI, then
we could have the best of both worlds.
But when we're comparing workflows like
this, the AI workflow definitely wins.
And then last but not least, the cost.
Of course, like I said, I would have had
to rent or own expensive gear worth
thousands and thousands of dollars, or
if you rent it, at least hundreds of
dollars per day. So, then if you compare
that to the AI credits I used for the
whole commercial, which was maybe in the
range of 50 to 100 dollars, it's a
no-brainer. And if you want access to
all the prompts I used in this video,
make sure to join my free school
community from the link below. And if
you enjoyed the video, make sure to
leave a like on it. But otherwise, I'll
see you in the next one.